wheatoncollege.edu 2016-11-27

# Digital Privacy Policy – Web | Wheaton College | Massachusetts

Wheaton College is committed to preserving and maintaining the privacy of visitors to our websites. Wheaton College wants the personal information of visitors to our website to remain as secure as reasonably possible. Hence, we have taken measures to protect such personal information from loss, misuse or alteration. You understand, however, that no website security procedures are foolproof. Therefore, you agree that the personal information you submit to the Wheaton College website is submitted at your own risk and that Wheaton College will not be liable to you for any breach of security or inadvertent disclosure of your personal information.

This Internet Privacy Policy will tell you what information we collect, how it is used and what your choices are. Please read this Internet Privacy Policy carefully.

**Use of Cookies; Collection and Use of Personal Information**

When you visit our website, we send one or more cookies - a small file containing a string of characters - to your computer that uniquely identifies your browser. Most browsers are initially set up to accept cookies, but you can reset your browser to refuse all cookies or to indicate when a cookie is being sent. However, some of our website’s features and services may not function properly if your cookies are disabled. We use cookies to improve the quality of our service by storing user preferences and tracking user trends, such as how people search.

For each visitor to our website, our web servers collect the Internet domain and Internet address of the computer you are using as well as essential technical information such as identification of the page or service you are requesting, type of browser and operating system you are using, and the date and time of access, but not the email address of visitors to our web page and sites. This information is recorded in the web server access log files. This information may be used for the purpose of evaluating website usage, compiling reports on website activity for internal use and providing other services related to website activity and internet usage.

We use third party service providers who assist us in aggregating and analyzing the data we collect from you and other website visitors and who may use your data to improve their services (for example, displaying customized content or advertising based on your use preferences, auditing, research and analysis to maintain, protect and improve their services, ensuring technical functioning of their network, and developing new services). These service providers may share aggregate, non-personal information with third parties.

Wheaton College collects the email addresses of those who communicate with us via email and those who make postings to our chat areas. Optional information is collected only if you choose to send it. For example, if you email Wheaton College, choose to complete an online form or make an online purchase, Wheaton College will collect the information you volunteer, such as your email information, survey information and/or site registrations and/or information you record in online forms. This may include:

  * The time that you sent an email.
  * Your name, email address, and the content of your email.
  * All the data you choose to fill in or confirm, including credit or debit card information if you are making a payment or donation, as well as information about other people if you are ordering a gift and want it sent directly to the recipient’s address.

Wheaton College uses personal information collected through our website to administer programs in which users have enrolled and to send program and marketing and promotion-related information to users. In addition, Wheaton College will analyze user information in aggregate form to assess its programs and determine its plans for the future. Except as set forth herein, Wheaton College will not use any personally identifiable information that it collects for marketing or promotional purposes and will not use personal information to contact visitors to our website for any purpose unless necessary for the enforcement of this Privacy Policy or Wheaton College’s policy on the use of the Wheaton College website or the wheatoncollege.edu domain.

Wheaton College does not intend to collect any information directly from children under the age of 13. If you are under the age of 13, you may use the Wheaton College website only with the involvement of a parent or guardian. In the event that Wheaton College learns that it has inadvertently collected information from a child under the age of 13, any and all such information will be promptly deleted from Wheaton College’s systems.

**Sharing Information**

Wheaton College will share personally identifiable information about you when one or more of the following conditions apply:

  * We have your consent to share the information; or
  * We respond to subpoenas, court orders or legal process; or
  * We employ other companies to perform functions on our behalf, such as processing credit card payments. They have access to personal information needed to perform their functions, but may not use this information for other purposes. (Note: Sharing and third-party use of information gathered by cookies, such as the Internet domain and Internet address of the computer you are using, identification of the page or service you are requesting, type of browser and operating system you are using, and the date and time of access, are discussed above.)

Except as otherwise provided herein, Wheaton College will not disclose any personal information it gathers about a visitor to our website that could be used to identify or contact such visitor. In the following limited circumstances, Wheaton College may release personal information to third parties: 1) to comply with valid legal requirements such as a law, regulation, subpoena or court order; or 2) in special cases such as a threat of physical violence to a visitor to our website or to others.

**Privacy Choices**

Visitors to the Wheaton College website may request that we remove the personal information that they provided to us from our databases and servers at any time by submitting a written request to Wheaton College at the address provided hereunder in Updates, Changes and Contacting Wheaton College. In addition, a visitor may refuse to allow the further collection or use of his or her personal information by submitting a written request to Wheaton College at the address provided hereunder in Updates, Changes and Contacting Wheaton College. Such requests do not apply to data associated with Wheaton user accounts.

If a visitor requests email notices or subscribes to a newsletter, he or she may UNSUBSCRIBE at any time by notifying Wheaton College at the address provided in such email notice or newsletter, or as provided hereunder in Updates, Changes and Contacting Wheaton College.

**Linked Sites**

As a courtesy, the Wheaton College Website includes links to third party websites. This Internet Privacy Policy does not apply to such third party websites, which are governed by their own terms of use and privacy policies.  
**Updates, Changes, and Contacting Wheaton College**

If you have any questions or suggestions with respect to this Internet Privacy Policy, or if you wish to contact Wheaton College to delete, modify, or review any of your personal information that we have stored, you may contact us by sending us an email or letter addressed as follows:

  * Email: [web@wheatoncollege.edu](mailto:webmaster@suffolk.edu)
  * U.S. mail: Wheaton College, Web Strategy, 26 E. Main St, Norton, MA 02766
